Hello everyone and welcome to English Pod.
My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine
and you've been with
us for a little while.
You've probably heard
some of our interview series already.
Well this is one of the
later episodes in that series. That's
right we're at part number nine.
We're reaching the end of our interview
and on this occasion we're going to ask our
employer a little bit of more
information about the company and more
importantly about the job.
Well this is a very important step like you
say it's at the end of the interview
so we're going to find out more details
about the job. Let's take
a listen to today's dialogue
we'll be back in a moment
to talk more about it.
Could you tell me a little about the
organization? For example how big is
your office here? Well in total we have
around 150 employees based in Hong Kong
with another 400 in our head
office in Beijing. The news desk staff in
Hong Kong has around 80 staff.
You see and how about the working hours?
Well as you know Rebecca in journalism
work hours are not exactly nine to five.
You could be on call at any
time but we do have to work
very unsosiable hours at times.
Well I'm used to that Mr. Parsons so that's
not really a shock for me.
Good as long as you understand that.
And when do you need to fill the
vacancy Mr. Parsons? Yesterday but no
we are hoping to start from
the beginning of next month.
That sounds like deal.
All right we're back so it's
obviously a very difficult job
and she asked some very key questions
so why don't we take a look at a couple of
the words and phrases used
there on language takeaway.
Language takeaway. The first word that
we have here for language takeaway is
workforce. That's right a workforce.
The company's workforce and that basically
means all the employees
that we have working for us.
That might not be in one office. Many
companies have two, three, even a hundred
offices so the workforce means all the
people who work for the company combined.
That's right so a workforce
and well she asked about the
the workforce and well it's
obviously a pretty big company 150
employees but he also
mentioned that the news desk staff
in Hong Kong comprises
around 80 people or 80 staff.
So this verb to comprise or in this case
it comprises means to
make up or to account for.
It's a very nice word to say it accounts
for it it makes up it it's the total.
It's the total right so in this case
the news desk staff has 80 people.
That's a very easy way to say it but
we could say it comprises 80 people.
It sounds a bit better.
That's right very good.
So now obviously she's going
to be a reporter or a journalist
and he said that she
should be on call at any time.
Okay on call is a phrase that we often
hear with jobs like journalism but also
medicine so doctors have to be
on call very often. This means that
you don't have to be in the office but
you have to be available to come into the
office.
So when someone calls you and they say
we have an emergency you have to be
available. That's right and you see it in
movies all the time you know
doctors are on call and maybe they're
already sleeping or maybe they're
out I don't know playing soccer with their
kids and they receive a phone
call and they have to go to the
hospital in that moment. It's because
they're on call that's because they're on
call very good and so
obviously this is a very
difficult thing for someone and
he explains that the work has very
unsociable hours at times.
Okay so you can say that
the hours are unsociable. You can
also say that a person is unsociable.
It basically means that it's
not very convenient for being
a social person or for going
out with friends and having many
many events to go to or fun
things to do in your personal life.
That's right so if a person is unsociable
it means that maybe that person is not
very outgoing or maybe is
always angry or grumpy so
that person doesn't get along well
with others. Right but in this case it
doesn't mean that it's a grumpy job
it just means that because she might
have to work at night very
often or on the weekends
it's very hard to have a social life.
That's right. Okay so obviously this job
is very difficult but in the end she
was really happy with it and she said
that sounds ideal her starting time.
So something this ideal if it's
perfect or great or the the top. That's
right many many people talk about the
ideal job right the perfect job. So
that's the job that you have in your mind
when you think of what is the best.
That's right so maybe my ideal job is
different from your ideal job.
That's right so you have ideal jobs or your
ideal house or your dream house.
Your ideal husband. That's right
so ideal idealism. So why don't we
listen to the dialogue again let's review
what Rebecca and
Mr. Parsons talked about and
we'll be back in a little
bit with fluency builder.
Could you tell me a little about the
organization for example how big is your
office here?
Well in total we have around 150 employees
based in Hong Kong with another
400 in our head office in Beijing.
The news desk staff in Hong Kong has
around 80 staff. You see and how about the
working hours? Well as you know
Rebecca and journalism work hours are not
exactly nine to five. You could be on
call at any time but we do have to work
very unsocial hours at times. Well I'm
used to that Mr. Parsons so that's not
really a shock for me.
Good as long as you understand that.
And when do you need to
fill the vacancy Mr. Parsons?
Yesterday but no we are hoping to
start from the beginning of next month.
That sounds like deal. All right we're
back so now we have four phrases for you
prepared on fluency builder. Fluency
builder. This first phrase is something
that we say all the time in English but
I think a lot of learners make mistakes
when they use it.
The phrase is how about? That's right.
So you see that Rebecca
was listening to Mr.
Parsons said and she said and how about
the working hours? So this is a way to say
and what are the working hours
but basically it's a way to continue the
conversation. You can say this in many
different ways but it basically means
and what about or please tell me about.
That's right. Now remember that many
English learners mistake the phrase
how about as if we're saying how are you
or how is it? No. You have to you
have to be following someone else in the
conversation. So for example I could say
you know what I'm gonna have a hamburger
with bacon. How about you Marco? What
are you gonna eat? How about you buy me
a cheeseburger? Okay so this is a
basically a way of saying okay well maybe
I'll have a cheeseburger or
what are you gonna have?
So now it's important to say don't
ever make this question. Don't ever ask
how about your weekend? No no no
no how was your weekend? That's right.
My weekend was great. How about yours?
How about yours? That's continuing the
conversation saying mine was good.
How was yours? Yeah okay so
remember that when they were talking
about the work hours he said that the
work hours are not exactly nine to five.
Okay so this is a kind of a set phrase
we use often in English because a
lot of people traditionally have worked
from nine a.m to five
p.m. They have a break
at lunch then they
go home. That's right.
So this is a kind of measure
for this is a way to describe
traditional working hours for traditional
jobs. So you can say yeah I have a
really nice nine to five job. You could
say I really don't want to work a nine
to five job. That's right so you don't
want a traditional job or you're working
from nine to five. Right most people I
think work a little bit longer than that
but this is this is just a way of saying
a traditional job. That's right okay nine
to five job. Now why don't we move
on to Rebecca saying that she is used to
working long hours or being on call.
Right so this
construction to be used to I'm
used to doing this is a way to say that
I already do this. This is my experience
or I have the habit of working unusual
hours. That's right so maybe for example
you live in a very noisy area in your
neighborhood and somebody comes and visits
you and they can't sleep because it's so
noisy. You're used to it. Oh you say
oh I don't mind I'm used to the noise.
But your friend who's visiting is
not used to it. Right they don't have
this noise at home so that's what
happens in the it can't sleep. So when you
are used to something you have the habit
or you're accustomed to it. That's right.
Okay and what about our last phrase? Our
last phrase comes at the end and Rebecca is
talking about the start and date for this
job. She wants to know when do you need to
fill the vacancy? Okay to fill the vacancy.
Now we have this word vacancy and that
means that it's available right. That's
right so vacancy is an available thing.
It could be a vacant place like an
apartment like an apartment or in this case
a vacancy in a company that means a job
that is available. That's right so she is
asking when she can fill the vacancies. So
we use the verb "fill" to fill a vacancy.
And this sounds a lot better than
saying hey when do I start working here?
Right. This is a polite
way to say when is the
job going to begin when do
you need to fill the vacancy by?
I guess another way of saying it
would be when is the starting date? Yes.
Okay but as we say
also fill the vacancy is a
very good option but
don't say when do I start
working or when do you
start? Yeah no we could
talk about that in a
minute. Let's listen first
to our dialogue one more
time we'll be back shortly.
Could you tell me a little
about the organization?
For example how
big is your office here?
Well in total we have
around 150 employees based
in Hong Kong with another
400 in our head office in Beijing.
The news desk staff
in Hong Kong has
around 80 staff. You see and
how about the working hours?
Well as you know Rebecca and journalism
work hours are not exactly nine to five.
You could be on call at any
time but we do have to work
very unsociable hours
at times. Well I'm used to
that Mr Parsons so that's
not really a shock for me.
Good as long as
you understand that.
And when do you need to
fill the vacancy Mr Parsons?
Yesterday but no we
are hoping to start from
the beginning of next
month. That sounds like deal.
So talking about
working hours being on
call or unsociable working
hours have you ever
had a job where you've had to
work maybe through the night?
Yes I used to work
in a movie theater
when I was in college. I had a
day job too so it was kind of a mess.
I was very unsociable
but I worked
in a movie theater and I
would start working at 6 p.
m. or 5 p.m. and I
would work until 2 or 3 a.
m. and so it was always
busiest on Friday and Saturday.
So I could never go
out with my friends.
Right so while everyone
was partying you were
at the movie theater.
Exactly or they would come
to the movies and I would
sneak in and bring them popcorn.
So these unusual
working hours it's very
interesting because
usually although it is a little
bit more of a sacrifice
they usually pay a little
bit better right? They do and
there are some advantages.
It means that you get
to sleep in really late.
Right you don't
have to wake up early
and you have the day off like
the entire day to do something.
Exactly. So I don't know what you
have you ever worked on usual hours?
Yes yes I used to work for a
newspaper and obviously people
like their newspaper
in the mornings.
Right and early. Right and
early we're talking about 6 a.m.
So obviously we would deliver
the newspapers around 1 a.
m. 2 a.m. from 1
a.m. to about 6 a.m.
So yeah pretty unusual
and very difficult because
for example some people for
them it's great to see the sunrise.
I've seen so many
sunrises and it's
not really romantic for
me anymore. We would call
you a night owl. Someone
who's more awake at night.
That's right and I still
am. So we were really
interested to know maybe
if you had any unusual
working hours or
do you work a 9 to 5?
Yeah you do you have a 9 to 5 job.
So come to our website EnglishPod.
com let us know and we'll
see everyone there. Bye!
[Music]